A Finding Aid to the Judith Wilson Papers, 1966-2010, in the Archives of American Art AAA.wilsjudi
Archives of American Art
Judith Wilson papers
1966-2010
AAA.wilsjudi
Archives of American Art
11.2 Linear feet
The papers of art historian Judith Wilson measure 11.2 linear feet and date from 1966 to 2010. Wilson's career is documented through correspondence with friends, colleagues, artists, universities, and art organizations; notebooks; files on writing projects, conferences, lectures, symposia and other professional activities; and a small amount of printed material. Also found is research material on artist Bob Thompson, including photographs, printed material, correspondence, notebooks and a documentary video recording. Additionally, the collection includes sound recordings of 71 interviews of artists and art collectors and six video recordings.
Wilson, Judith, 1952-
Biographical/Historical note
Judith Wilson (1952- ) is an art historian in San Francisco, California. Wilson began her career as an editor for Ms. Magazine in 1975. In 1979 she wrote a profile of Alma Thomas for that magazine, after which she began writing regularly about visual art and cultural politics, reviewing exhibitions, writing feature articles, and serving as guest editor for several publications. Her research interests included African-American art and black visual culture. She received her Ph.D. in art history from Yale University with a dissertation on the artist Bob Thompson. Her teaching career included full-time positions in art history at University of Virginia, Yale, and the University of California, Irvine, as well as part-time and visiting professorships at several other schools. In 2006 she retired from the University of California, Irvine after eight years. During her career Wilson served on editorial and advisory boards for art publications and wrote many catalog essays, contributed to anthologies, and presented numerous conference papers, many of which were later published.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was donated in 2012 by Judith Wilson-Pates.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Office. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art historian Judith Wilson measure 11.2 linear feet and date from 1966 to 2010. Wilson's career is documented through correspondence with friends, colleagues, artists, universities, and art organizations; notebooks; files on writing projects, conferences, lectures, symposia and other professional activities; and a small amount of printed material. Also found is research material on artist Bob Thompson, including photographs, printed material, correspondence, notebooks and a documentary video recording. Additionally, the collection includes sound recordings of 71 interviews of artists and art collectors and six video recordings.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 9 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1975-2009 (1.3 linear feet; Boxes 1-2)
Series 2: Notebooks, 1977-2008 (1.7 linear feet; Boxes 2-3)
Series 3: Writing Projects, 1972-2010 (1.7 linear feet; Boxes 4-5)
Series 4: Conferences, Lectures, and Symposia, 1978-2009 (2.0 linear feet; Boxes 5-7)
Series 5: Professional Records, 1979-2009 (1.0 linear foot; Boxes 7-9)
Series 6: Research Material on Bob Thompson, 1966-2006 (1.8 linear feet; Boxes 8-10)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1981-2010 (0.5 linear feet; Box 10)
Series 8: Interviews, 1978-2008 (1.0 linear foot; Boxes 11-12)
Series 9: Video Recordings, 1979-2007 (4 folders; Box 12)
Thompson, Bob, 1937-1966; Art historians--California--San Francisco; Interviews; Photographs; Sound recordings; Video recordings
- Correspondence, 1975-2009; Series 1; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Scope and Contents note
  Found here is Wilson's correspondence with colleagues, scholars, artists, arts organizations, and universities. A small amount of personal correspondence with friends is also included. Of note is extensive correspondence with artists Houston Conwill, Judy Chicago, Ana Mendieta, Howardena Pindell, Adrian Piper, and Raymond Saunders; as well as art historians Kellie Jones, Theresa Leininger-Miller, Lucy Lippard, Eunice Lipton, Kymberly Pinder, Richard Powell, and Moira Roth.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Additional files of student correspondence and letters of recommendations are arranged at the end of the series.
  - A, 1982-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B, 1979-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Wesley R. Cochran, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Houston Conwill, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - C, 1981-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D, 1981-1995; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - E-F, 1986-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Shifra M. Goldman, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - G, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jennifer Harper, 1993-2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cynthia Hawkins, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bill Hutson, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - H, 1981-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Institute of International Visual Arts, 1996-2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kellie Jones, circa 1987-1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Steven Jones, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - I-J, circa 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - K, 1983-1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Theresa Leininger-Miller, 1989-2002 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Lucy Lippard, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Eunice Lipton, circa 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - L, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Chuck Martin, 1982-1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ana Mendieta, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - M, 2002; 1979-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - N-O, 1980-1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - James T. Parker, 1998; 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 28-32)
  - Howardena Pindell, 1980-1990; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Kymberly Pinder, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Adrian Piper, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Rick Powell, 1980-1996 (Box 1, Folder 37-39)
  - P, 1981-1995 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Moira Roth, 1988-1998 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - R, 1986-1995 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Raymond Saunders, circa 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - S, 1982-1995; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - T, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - U-V, 1994-1997; 1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Alice Walker, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - W, 1985-2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified, 1978-2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Students, 1986-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1989-2004 (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
- Notebooks, 1977-2008; Series 2; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Wilson's notebooks include notes from interviews with artists and collectors, studio visits, exhibitions, conferences, and other activities. They also document project ideas and research sources. Researchers should note that notebooks regarding research on Bob Thompson are included in Series 6.
  Notebooks are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Notebooks, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 9-14)
  - Notepads, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Notebooks, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
  - Notebook, "Unbound Notes", circa 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Notebooks, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Notebooks, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
  - Notebook, "Projects", 1986-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - Notebook, "Art Journal", 1989-2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, 1990-1991; 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7-11)
  - Notebooks, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Notebook, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, 1997-2003 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, circa 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Notebooks, 1999-2008 (Box 3, Folder 17-19)
- Writing Projects, 1972-2010; Series 3; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Found here are Judith Wilson's files regarding her writing projects, including magazine and journal articles, book projects, exhibition catalog essays, and guest editorships. Some files contain documentation for writings that were never published. Documents may include project correspondence, draft writings, planning documents and agreements, research material, and publications. Not all files contain drafts or final published versions of the writings. Writing projects of note include articles on Alma Thomas, Henry Ossawa Tanner, and Adrian Piper, as well as catalog essays on Hale Woodruff, Alison Saar, and Sargent Johnson. Interviews conducted for writing projects are included in Series 8: Interviews.
  Folders are grouped by type of project and further arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Article, "Alma Thomas: A One-Woman Art Movement," Ms. Magazine, circa 1978; 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Article, "Buying Art: The Big Picture," Essence, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Article (Unwritten) on Black Art for Essence, circa 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Article (Unwritten) on Black Women Artists for Essence, circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Article, "Three Women Artists," Essence, circa 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Article Proposal (Unpublished) on Black Bohemianism for Village Voice, circa 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Article (Unpublished) on Alison Saar for Village Voice, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Article, "Romare Bearden," Modern Black Men Magazine, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Article, "Lifting 'The Veil': Henry O. Tanner's The Banjo Lesson and The Thankful Poor," Contributions in Black Studies, 1996-1997; 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Articles, Black Arts Annual, 1987-1997 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Article, "Adrian Piper," Third Text, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Article (Unpublished), "Movement and Light: The Futurist Dance Manifesto," Rutgers Art Review, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Article Reprint, "Down to the Crossroads: The Art of Alison Saar," Callaloo, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Article for Black Women Film and Video Artists, 1996-2000 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Article for Grolier Incorporated, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Book Project (Unpublished), "Black Visual Studies", 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Book Project (Unrealized), "Undercurrents & Overviews", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Catalog Essay, "Lorraine O'Grady: Critical Interventions", 1984-1992 (Box 4, Folder 24-26)
  - Catalog Essay (Unrealized), "Mojo Working", 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Catalog Essay, "Autobiography: In Her Own Image", 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Catalog Essay, "Lines of Vision: Drawings by Contemporary Women", 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Catalog Essay, "Hale Woodruff", circa 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 30-33)
    Includes 1 sound cassette of interview with Mrs. Sadella T. Williams by Steven L. Jones
  - Catalog Essay, "Down to the Crossroads: The Art of Alison Saar", 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
    Includes 2 sound cassettes and transcript of Alison Saar interview by Judith Wilson
  - Catalog Essay, "The Rage of Children", 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Catalog Essay, "Disputed Identities", 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Catalog Essay, "This is My Body: This is My Blood", 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Catalog Essay, "Sargent Johnson and Modernism", 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Catalog Essay, "Alma Thomas: A Retrospective of the Paintings", circa 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
  - Catalog Essay, New Jersey State Museum African-American Fine Arts Collection, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Catalog Essay, "Sargent Johnson: Afro-California Modernist", 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 10-12)
  - Catalog Essay, "Recollected: Selections From the Studio Museum in Harlem", 2010 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Collection of Essays (Unpublished), "Optical Illusions: Race, Gender, Culture, & the Visual Arts", 1990-1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Essay, "Beauty Rites" for African American women Artists: A Visual and Critical Reference, 1993-2000 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Essay for Modern Art in the USA: Issues and Controversies of the 20th Century, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Guest Editor, "Cashing in on Fine Art," Black Enterprise, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
  - Proposal, "The Visual Arts of Black America: An Encyclopedia", 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Seminar Paper, "Movement and Light: The Futurist Dance Manifesto", 1982; 1989 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
  - Statement for International Review of African American Art, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Conferences, Lectures, and Symposia, 1978-2009; Series 4; 2 Linear feet Boxes 5-7
  Found here is Wilson's documentation on her participation in conferences, lectures, and symposia. Files may include correspondence, planning and travel documents, panelist biographies, programs and event publications, drafts of Wilson's lectures, and slide lists. Several files also include sound cassette recordings of events, as well as electronic discs (CD and DVD) containing planning documents and draft lectures.
  Folders are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - "May 24 Dialogue," National Arts Consortium, 1978; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
  - "A Symposium: African American Art," Everson Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Exploring the Unknown: Black Women Artists," Women's Caucus for Art Conference, 1981-1982; Includes 3 sound cassettes. (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
  - Lecture, Miami Dade Community College, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Kaprow Lecture, 1984 November 30; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "Kind of Blue" Panel, Northeastern University, 1986; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - "Writing About the Black Artist," Hatch-Billops Archives, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "Beyond Universality" Lecture, Washington Project for the Arts, 1987-1988; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Women's Caucus for Art National Conference, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Lecture, Syracuse University, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Panel on "The Figurative '50s", 1988 October 14; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, Museum Aid Program Conference, circa 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Abstract Expressionism: The Missing Link," Jamaica Arts Center, 1989 January 14; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Black Aesthetic Panel, New Museum, 1989 March 28; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Workshop, Barnard Feminist Art History Conference, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Critical Comment" Conference, St. Michael's College, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Women in the Arts" Conference, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Reinventing the American Scene: A Symposium," Newark Museum, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Contemporary Art by Women of Color," Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Defacto Racism in the Visual Arts," College Art Association, 1989-1990; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - "Race & Art," World Monitor TV, 1990 January 4; 1 Electronic discs (CD) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Shades of Gray in the Black Aesthetic," S.E.C.C.A., 1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "NOVAE: William H. Johnson and Bob Thompson", 1990; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Photography Sesquicentennial Project Conference, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "The Decade Show," The New Museum, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Seminar, Whitney Independent Study Program, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - College Art Association Conference, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Symposium: Cultural Continuities in the Arts," Smith College, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - National Conference of the Society for Photographic Education, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Women in the Arts Symposium," Gettysburg College, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - "State of the Art: Recent Developments in African-American Art," UVA Women's Center, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Lecture, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - AICA Panel, College Art Association Meeting, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - "Representation and Value," The Drawing Center, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Lecture, Maryland Institute College of Art, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - "The Art of Archibald Motley, Jr.," Studio Museum in Harlem, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - "Art and Social Responsibility: A Community Forum", 1992 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - "A Postmortem on Postmodernism," New York University, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Eunice Lipton Lecture, University of Virginia, 1993 November 11; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Middlesex University Conference, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - "Surfing the 'Black' Diasporic Web", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - "Post-Mortem" Symposium, Stanford University, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Ford Conference, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Black Women's Seminar, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - American Photography Institute National Graduate Seminar, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Symposium, "50th Anniversary of the School of Visual Arts", 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - MIT List Visual Arts Center Symposium, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art Symposium, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Lecture, UCLA, 1998; 2002 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Lecture, New School for Social Research, 1998-1999; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Docent Talk, UCLA Hammer Museum, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Situation Critical: African-American Writers on African American Artists," Museum of Modern Art, 1999 March 16; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Pop Art and Vernacular Cultures," Institute of International Visual Arts, 2006; 1 Electronic discs (CD) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "Extended Provocations," University of California, Irvine, 2007; 2 Electronic discs (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "LA Avant-Garde," Getty Research Institute, 2007-2008; 2 Electronic discs (CD) (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
  - "Black Artists in LA 1960-1980" Colloquium, Hammer Museum, 2008-2009 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Porter Colloquium, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Music Used for Lectures, 1989; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Professional Records, 1979-2009; Series 5; 1 Linear feet Boxes 7-8
  Professional records document Wilson's participation in juries, advisory committees, editorial boards, and exhibitions, as well as a few teaching records and other records of professional meetings. Also found are letters to the editor and reader's reports for various articles, book projects, and manuscripts. Files may include correspondence, notes, meeting minutes and agendas, publications, and draft writings by others.
  - Advisory Council, Third Text, 1993-1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Acting Assistant Professor, UVA, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Anonymous Was A Woman Award, 1980-2001 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Art Advisory Committee, The Contemporary, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Assistant Professor, Yale University, 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Book Review, Signs, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Caucus of African-American Art Professionals, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Co-Guest Editor, CAA Art Journal, 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Consultant, "Voices in Exile" Film Project, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Contributing and Advisory Board, Callaloo, 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Editorial Board, American Art, 1996-2004 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Editorial Board, CAA Art Journal, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Editorial Board, University Press of Virginia, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition, "Afro-American Art in the 20th Century: Three Episodes," Bronx Museum of the Arts, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition, "Afro-American Abstraction," PS 1, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Fantastic Coalition of Women in the Arts, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Johnnie L. Cochran Jr. Art Fund, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Juror, Maryland State Arts Council, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Letters to the Editor, Women Artists News, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Letter to the Editor, New York Times Book Review, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Letter to the Editor, Washington Post, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript Review, Signs, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Morse Fellowship, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Newark Museum Reinstallation Project, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Project Advisory Council, The Studio Museum in Harlem, 1989-1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Reader's Reports on Various Articles, Book Projects, and Manuscripts, 1993-2004 (Box 8, Folder 16-19)
  - Review of "I'll Make Me a World" Rough Cuts, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - San Francisco Municipal Arts Funding, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Tenure Review, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - UC Irvine Job Applications, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Unrealized Exhibition Project, "New World/New People," Alternative Museum, circa 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 24-26)
  - Visiting Critic, Jerome Foundation Fellowship Program, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Visual Feminists Meeting, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Whitney Scholars Advisory Committee, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, 2009; 1996 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Research Material on Bob Thompson, 1966-2006; Series 6; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 8-10
  Judith Wilson's research material regarding artist Bob Thompson includes research correspondence, extensive research notebooks, index to the notebook, slide lists, and general research material. The general research files include photographs of artwork by Thompson, catalogs and announcements for exhibitions of his work, press clippings and a few handwritten lists. Additionally there are three electronic discs (floppy, CD, and DVD) containing research files. Wilson conducted most of this research for her dissertation, "Garden of Music: The Search for Creative Community in the Art and Life of Bob Thompson (1937-1966)." A copy of the dissertation is also included here. "Bob Thompson Happening!", a documentary by Dorothy Beskind, is available on one videocassette and duplicate digitial copy.
  - Dissertation, "Garden of Music: The Search For Creative Community in the Art and Life of Bob Thompson (1937-1966)", 1995 (Box 8, Folder 31-33)
  - Essay, "Garden of Music: The Search for Creative Community in the Art and Life of Bob Thompson (1937-1996)", 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 34-35)
  - Publication Proofs, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Address/Phone File, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, 1982-2002 (Box 9, Folder 4-8)
  - Research Material, 2006; 1966-1998; Includes 3 electronic discs (1 floppy disk, 1 CD, 1 DVD). (Box 9, Folder 9-15)
  - Lists of Bob Thompson Related Slides, circa 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Index to Bob Thompson Notebooks, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 17-19)
  - Notebook A, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Notebook B, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Notebook C, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Notebook D, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Notebook E, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Notebook F, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notebook G, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notebook H, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notebook I, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notebook J, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Notebook K, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Bob Thompson Happening!" Whitney Museum of American Art (1965), 2006; circa 1990s; 1 Electronic discs (CD) Duplicate video recording; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Printed Material, 1981-2010; Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet Box 10
  A small amount of printed material includes books, magazines, and other publications containing writings by Wilson or other mentions of her work. Also found are several issues of Black Studies Correspondence and a few exhibition announcements.
  - Black Studies Correspondence Journal, 1987-1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Book, Art, Women, California 1950-2000, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Book, The Feminism and Visual Culture Reader, 2003, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Book, Mythologizing Always by Patricia Jones, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1988-2008 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1996; 1998; 1988 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)